AHMAD RAZA

Brooklyn, NY 11230

linkedin.com/in/Razatastic ● github.com/Razatastic ● me@razatastic.com ● 347-828-6637

SUMMARY

Collaborative, creative computer science student with experience in Object-Oriented Programming, web development and Linux administration. Strong foundation in programming logic, problem solving and cross-platform coding. Winner of the Codecademy prize at the 2018 CUNY Hackathon.

EDUCATION

B.S., Computer Science, Brooklyn College/CUNY

Graduation expected - May 2019

- **GPA:** 3.7
- Relevant Coursework: Advance C++, Computer Architecture, Discrete Structures, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Design and Implementation

PROJECTS

CommuniTii, New York, NY

April 2018 - Present

- Developed an app for non-profits that encourages people to socialize in-person and give back to the community through the use of gamification. (React Native Express, Firebase, Adobe XD)
- Awarded Codecademy Prize at the 2018 CUNY Hackathon.
- Accepted into the CUNY Startup Accelerator program.

EXPERIENCE

STAPLES, INC., Brooklyn, NY

July 2015 - November 2015

EasyTech Sales Associate (Full-time)

- Achieved weekly sales goals of \$2,500 by engaging 30 customers daily by asking open-ended questions and providing recommendations based on interests and needs.
- Built relationships with Certified Tech Associates to create synergy across all technology departments.
- Resolved technical and non-technical customer concerns over the phone and in-person.
- Participated in bi-monthly team meetings to learn about new technologies, products and services.

NEW YORK CITY DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION, Brooklyn, NY

September 2011 – November 2014

Student Aide (Full-time & Part-time)

- Collaborated with administration and aided in solving technical problems that arose day-to-day.
- Handled complex computer troubleshooting issues for 5,000+ students and 200 faculty members weekly.
- Regulated 3,000+ workstations by setting up networks and reimaging/ghosting entire classrooms to maintain a fully working environment.
- Managed and updated spreadsheet of inventory consisting of hardware components weekly.
- Provided onsite training and assistance to roughly 2-3 new employees every term.

LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY, TANDON SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, Brooklyn, NY

February 2016

Volunteer

• Participated in the annual NYU Hackathon assisting participants create a working development environment.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Technical: Java, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Firebase, Bootstrap, SASS, Git/SVN, Electron, Expo, Bash scripting, Adobe XD, Figma, GCP, Parallels, VMWare, VM VirtualBox, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code and Linux/Unix.

Language: Fluent Urdu and Conversational French.

Interests: Technology, Entrepreneurship, and Traveling.